amigurumipatterns.net 2018-01-22

# Amigurumipatterns.net - Privacy Policy

**What information do we collect?**   
Surfing on the website: You may visit our site anonymously. Our system does determine the country you are surfing from through your IP address, which is used to add customary localised VAT to the patterns and for displaying localised banners on our website. We store this data on a cookie on your computer so the system doesn't have to check your country on each visit. 

When registering on our website: we collect your email address and password. This password is stored securely on our server so when the data is breached, this should not impact your accounts on other websites. You can also choose to log in with your Facebook account in which case we store your Facebook email address. 

When ordering on our site: we collect your name, e-mail address. We also receive from Paypal your country of origin, your full address (if you've purchase a physical item) and the exact time of purchase. We store any transaction in our database for your and our reference. 

**What do we use your information for?**

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:   
; To personalize your experience (your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)   
; To improve our website (we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)   
; To improve customer service (your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)   
; To process transactions Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.   
; To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature   
; To send periodic emails  
The email address you provide for order processing, may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email. 

**How do we protect your information?**

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information. Your data is stored permanently on our server, unless if you contact us to remove any information that could identify you. 

**Do we use cookies?**

Yes (Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information 

We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business. 

**Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. 

Third party links 

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites. 

**California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent. 

**Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. 

**Can I check or (permanently) delete my data?**  
Yes. Send an email with your full name and email address to hello@amigurumipatterns.net with your request. If requested, we will delete any personal information from our data and anonymize any purchases you have made in the past. As the data is deleted (not just inactivated) we will not be able to restore your data in the future. 

**Your Consent**

By using our site, you consent to our online privacy policy. 

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page. 

This policy is powered by Trust Guard PCI compliance.
